https://www.ncu.edu/privacy

Grants and Scholarships
About NCUWho We AreMission, Vision, Values, & Strategic Plan
Grants and Scholarships
About NCUWho We AreMission, Vision, Values, & Strategic Plan
December 23, 2019
Northcentral University values its users' privacy. This Privacy Policy ("Policy") will help you understand how we collect and use personal information from those who visit our website or make use of our online facilities and services, and what we will and will not do with the information we collect. Our Policy has been designed and created to ensure those affiliated with Northcentral University of our commitment and realization of our obligation not only to meet, but to exceed, most existing privacy standards.
We reserve the right to make changes to this Policy at any given time. If you want to make sure that you are up to date with the latest changes, we advise you to frequently visit this page. If at any point in time Northcentral University decides to make use of any personally identifiable information on file, in a manner vastly different from that which was stated when this information was initially collected, the user or users shall be promptly notified by email. Users at that time shall have the option as to whether to permit the use of their information in this separate manner.
Please note that this Policy does not govern the collection and use of information by companies that Northcentral University does not control, nor by individuals not employed or managed by us. If you visit a website that we mention or link to, be sure to review its privacy policy before providing the site with information. It is highly recommended and suggested that you review the privacy policies and statements of any website you choose to use or frequent to better understand the way in which websites garner, make use of and share the information collected.
Specifically, this Policy will inform you of the following:
What personally identifiable information is collected from you through our website;
Why we collect personally identifiable information and the legal basis for such collection;
How we use the collected information and with whom it may be shared;
What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data; and
The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.
Information We Collect
It is always up to you whether to disclose personally identifiable information to us, although if you elect not to do so, we reserve the right not to register you as a user or provide you with any products or services. This website collects various types of information, such as:
Voluntarily provided information which may include your name, address, email address, billing and/or credit card information etc. which may be used when you purchase products and/or services and to deliver the services you have requested.
Information automatically collected when visiting our website, which may include cookies, third party tracking technologies and server logs.
In addition, Northcentral University may have the occasion to collect non-personal anonymous demographic information, such as age, gender, Zip Code, as well as the type of browser you are using, IP address, or type of operating system, which will assist us in providing and maintaining superior quality service.
Northcentral University may also deem it necessary, from time to time, to follow websites that our users may frequent to gleam what types of services and products may be the most popular to customers or the general public.
Please rest assured that this site will only collect personal information that you knowingly and willingly provide to us by way of surveys, completed membership forms, and emails. It is the intent of this site to use personal information only for the purpose for which it was requested, and any additional uses specifically provided for on this Policy.
Our site collects site usage information (not personally identifiable) for the purposes of improving our site content and user experience. The type of information we gather can include the following.
Bing Ads, LinkedIn Ads, DoubleClick, LiveIntent, Simpli.fi, AcuityPlatform, Taboola Monetize Content and Target PerformancePersonal Data: Cookies, Usage Data, Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website
Facebook Audience Network, Facebook AdsPersonal Data: Cookies, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and Usage Data
OutbrainPersonal Data: Cookies and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
CVENTPersonal Data: Cookies
HelpSquad, LivePersonPersonal Data: Cookies, Usage Data, Preserves users states across page requests
JornayaPersonal Data: Cookies, Unique user ID that recognizes the user on returning visits
Pardot, AdRollPersonal Data: Cookies, User Data
SonobiPersonal Data: Cookies, used to distribute traffic to the website on several servers in order to optimize response times
UIDPersonal Data: Cookies, Unique user ID that recognizes the user on returning visits
UTM Parameters (campaign, medium, source)Personal Data: Cookies, User Data, Unique user ID that recognizes the user on returning visits to help with attribution
JobvitePersonal Data: Cookies, Registers a timestamp with the exact time of when the user accessed the website. Used by Google Analytics to calculate the duration of a website visit
Cookie ConsentPersonal Data: Cookies, stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain
InstinctiveAds, PushCrew, SiteImprovePersonal Data: Cookies, Used by the content network, Cloudflare, to identify trusted web traffic
Visual Website Optimizer (VWO)Personal Data: Cookies, Usage Data, Preserves users states across page requests
DrupalPersonal Data: Cookies, Usage Data, Preserves users states across page requests
HotJarPersonal Data: Cookies, Usage Data
AnalyticsGoogle Analytics, Google Tag Manager, GAID, Adobe Analytics, Google Analytics with anonymized IP and Salesforce Analytics CloudPersonal Data: Cookies and Usage Data
Google Analytics for FirebasePersonal Data: Cookies, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and Usage Data
User ID extension for Google Analytics, GIDPersonal Data: Cookies, Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website
Opt Out of Analytics TrackingYou can choose to opt out of having site activity logged by clicking here.
Use of Cookies and Web Beacons
A “cookie” is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.
The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page, which helps Northcentral University recall your specific information on subsequent visits.
A “Web beacon” is typically a small transparent graphic image that works with cookies to count and recognize users, and track movement from point to point within a server network.
Northcentral University Web sites use cookies to help you personalize your online experience. When you return to the same Northcentral University Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved so that you can easily use the features that you customized.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Northcentral University services or Web sites you visit.
Why We Collect Information and For How Long
We are collecting your data for several reasons:
To better understand your needs and provide you with the services you have requested;
To fulfill our legitimate interest in improving our services and products;
To send you promotional emails containing information we think you may like when we have your consent to do so;
To contact you to fill out surveys or participate in other types of market research, when we have your consent to do so;
To customize our website according to your online behavior and personal preferences.
The data we collect from you will be stored for no longer than necessary. The length of time we retain said information will be determined based upon the following criteria: the length of time your personal information remains relevant; the length of time it is reasonable to keep records to demonstrate that we have fulfilled our duties and obligations; any limitation periods within which claims might be made; any retention periods prescribed by law or recommended by regulators, professional bodies or associations; the type of contract we have with you, the existence of your consent, and our legitimate interest in keeping such information as stated in this Policy.
Use of Information Collected
Northcentral University does not now, nor will it in the future, sell, rent or lease any of its customer lists and/or names to any third parties.
Northcentral University may collect and may make use of personal information to assist in the operation of our website and to ensure delivery of the services you need and request. At times, we may find it necessary to use personally identifiable information as a means to keep you informed of other possible products and/or services that may be available to you from https://nationaled.org/ and its subsidiaries.
Northcentral University and its subsidiaries may also be in contact with you with regards to completing surveys and/or research questionnaires related to your opinion of current or potential future services that may be offered.
Northcentral University uses various third-party social media features including but not limited to https://www.facebook.com/NorthcentralU, https://twitter.com/NorthcentralU, https://www.youtube.com/c/ncuedu, https://www.linkedin.com/school/northcentral-university, https://www.instagram.com/northcentral_u, https://www.linkedin.com/company/nationaleducation-partners/jobs/?viewAs..., https://www.facebook.com/JFKUniv, https://www.linkedin.com/school/john-f.-kennedy-university/, https://twitter.com/jfkuniv and other interactive programs. These may collect your IP address and require cookies to work properly. These services are governed by the privacy policies of the providers and are not within Northcentral University control.
Disclosure of Information
Northcentral University may not use or disclose the information provided by you except under the following circumstances:
as necessary to provide services or products you have ordered;
in other ways described in this Policy or to which you have otherwise consented;
in the aggregate with other information in such a way so that your identity cannot reasonably be determined;
as required by law, or in response to a subpoena or search warrant;
to outside auditors who have agreed to keep the information confidential;
as necessary to enforce the Terms of Service;
as necessary to maintain, safeguard and preserve all the rights and property of Northcentral University.
Non-Marketing Purposes
Northcentral University greatly respects your privacy. We do maintain and reserve the right to contact you if needed for non-marketing purposes (such as bug alerts, security breaches, account issues, and/or changes in Northcentral University products and services). In certain circumstances, we may use our website, newspapers, or other public means to post a notice.
Children under the age of 13
Northcentral University website is not directed to, and does not knowingly collect personal identifiable information from, children under the age of thirteen (13). If it is determined that such information has been inadvertently collected on anyone under the age of thirteen (13), we shall immediately take the necessary steps to ensure that such information is deleted from our system's database, or in the alternative, that verifiable parental consent is obtained for the use and storage of such information. Anyone under the age of thirteen (13) must seek and obtain parent or guardian permission to use this website.
Unsubscribe or Opt-Out
All users and visitors to our website have the option to discontinue receiving communications from us by way of email or newsletters. To discontinue or unsubscribe from our website please send an email that you wish to unsubscribe to Dataprotection@nationaled.org. If you wish to unsubscribe or opt-out from any third-party websites, you must go to that specific website to unsubscribe or opt-out. Northcentral University will continue to adhere to this Policy with respect to any personal information previously collected.
Links to Other Websites
Our website does contain links to affiliate and other websites. Northcentral University does not claim nor accept responsibility for any privacy policies, practices and/or procedures of other such websites. Therefore, we encourage all users and visitors to be aware when they leave our website and to read the privacy statements of every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy Agreement applies only and solely to the information collected by our website.
Notice to European Union Users
Northcentral University operations are located primarily in the United States. If you provide information to us, the information will be transferred out of the European Union (EU) and sent to the United States. (The adequacy decision on the EU-US Privacy became operational on August 1, 2016. This framework protects the fundamental rights of anyone in the EU whose personal data is transferred to the United States for commercial purposes. It allows the free transfer of data to companies that are certified in the US under the Privacy Shield.) By providing personal information to us, you are consenting to its storage and use as described in this Policy.
Your Rights as a Data Subject
Under the regulations of the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") of the EU you have certain rights as a Data Subject. These rights are as follows:
The right to be informed: this means we must inform you of how we intend to use your personal data and we do this through the terms of this Policy.
The right of access: this means you have the right to request access to the data we hold about you and we must respond to those requests within one month. You can do this by sending an email to dataprotection@ncu.edu.
The right to rectification: this means that if you believe some of the date, we hold is incorrect, you have the right to have it corrected. You can do this by logging into your account with us, or by sending us an email with your request.
The right to erasure: this means you can request that the information we hold be deleted, and we will comply unless we have a compelling reason not to, in which case you will be informed of same. You can do this by sending an email to dataprotection@ncu.edu.
The right to restrict processing: this means you can change your communication preferences or opt-out of certain communications. You can do this by sending an email to dataprotection@nationaled.org.
The right of data portability: this means you can obtain and use the data we hold for your own purposes without explanation. If you wish to request a copy of your information, contact us at dataprotection@ncu.edu.
The right to object: this means you can file a formal objection with us regarding our use of your information with regard to third parties, or its processing where our legal basis is our legitimate interest in it. To do this, please send an email to dataprotection@ncu.edu.
In addition to the rights above, please rest assured that we will always aim to encrypt and anonymize your personal information whenever possible. We also have protocols in place in the unlikely event that we suffer a data breach and we will contact you if your personal information is ever at risk. For more details regarding our security protections see the section below or visit our website at https://nationaled.org/.
Your California Privacy Rights
If you are a California resident, you have the following rights. We will honor requests received to the extent required by applicable law and within the time provided by law.
Right to Access and Information regarding Personal Information. You have the right to request that we disclose to you the categories and specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you. Specifically, you have the right to request that we disclose the following to you, in each case in the twelve-month period preceding your request:
the categories of personal information we have collected about you;
the categories of sources from which the personal information is collected;
our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling personal information;
the categories of third parties with whom we share personal information;
the specific pieces of information we have collected about you;
the categories of personal information about you, if any, that we have disclosed for monetary or other valuable consideration and the categories of third parties to which we have disclosed the information, by category or categories of personal information for each third party to which we disclosed the personal information; and
the categories of personal information about you that we disclosed for a business purpose.
We will deliver personal information that we are required by law to disclose to you in the manner required by law within 45 days after receipt of a verifiable request, unless we notify you that we require additional time to respond, in which case we will respond within such additional period of time required by law. We may deliver the personal information to you electronically or by mail at your option. If electronically, then we will deliver the information in a portable and, to the extent technically feasible, in a readily useable format that allows you to transmit the information from one entity to another without hindrance.
Right to Deletion of Personal Information. You have the right to request that we delete Personal Information about you that we have collected from you.
Right to Opt Out.
You have the right to opt out of the disclosure of personal information about you for monetary or other valuable consideration. To opt-out, click Do Not Sell My Personal Information.
We may not discriminate against you because of your exercise of any of the foregoing rights, or any other rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act, including by:
Denying you goods or services;
Charging different prices or rates for goods or services, including through the use of discounts or other benefits or imposing penalties;
Providing you a different level or quality of goods or services; or
Suggesting that you will receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.
Security
Northcentral University takes precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline. Wherever we collect sensitive information (e.g. credit card information), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a lock icon in the address bar and looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the webpage.
While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers and servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. This is all done to prevent any loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure or modification of the user's personal information under our control.
The company also uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) for authentication and private communications to build users' trust and confidence in the internet and website use by providing simple and secure access and communication of credit card and personal information.
Acceptance of Terms
By using this website, you are hereby accepting the terms and conditions stipulated within the Privacy Policy Agreement. If you are not in agreement with our terms and conditions, then you should refrain from further use of our sites. In addition, your continued use of our website following the posting of any updates or changes to our terms and conditions shall mean that you agree and acceptance of such changes.
How to Contact Us
If you have any questions or concerns regarding the Privacy Policy Agreement related to our website, please feel free to contact us at the following email, telephone number or mailing address.
Email: dataprotection@ncu.edu
Telephone Number: 844-628-2611
Mailing Address:
Northcentral University
8667 E Hartford Dr Suite #100
Scottsdale, Arizona 85255
The data controller responsible for your personal information for the purposes of GDPR compliance is:
Data Protection Officer
dataprotection@ncu.edu
8667 E. Hartford Dr. Suite #100
Scottsdale, AZ 85255
Request Information
Request Information
My Interests
Program of Interest *
Select DegreeEducation SpecialistEducation Specialist in Educational LeadershipDoctor of Business AdministrationDoctor of Criminal JusticeDoctor of Philosophy in Business AdministrationDoctor of EducationDoctor of Education in Educational LeadershipDoctor of Education in Instructional DesignDoctor of Health AdministrationDoctor of Nursing PracticeDoctor of Philosophy in Computer ScienceDoctor of Philosophy in Data ScienceDoctor of Philosophy in EducationDoctor of Philosophy in Educational LeadershipDoctor of Philosophy in Human Resource ManagementDoctor of Philosophy in Instructional DesignDoctor of Philosophy in Organizational LeadershipDoctor of Philosophy in PsychologyDoctor of Philosophy in Technology and Innovation ManagementDoctor of Public AdministrationDoctorate of Marriage and Family TherapyDoctor of Philosophy in Marriage & Family TherapyJuris DoctorMaster of Business AdministrationMaster of Legal StudiesMaster of EducationMaster of Education in Educational LeadershipMaster of Arts in Marriage and Family TherapyMaster of Arts in PsychologyMaster of Arts in TeachingMaster of Health AdministrationMaster of Human Resource ManagementMaster of Public AdministrationMaster of Science in AccountingMaster of Science in Child and Adolescent Developmental PsychologyMaster of Science in Instructional DesignMaster of Science in Computer ScienceMaster of Science in CybersecurityMaster of Science in Data ScienceMaster of Science in Educational PsychologyMaster of Science in Forensic PsychologyMaster of Science Health PsychologyMaster of Science in Industrial/Organizational PsychologyMaster of Science in Information TechnologyMaster of Science in NursingMaster of Science in Organizational LeadershipMaster of Science in Technology and Innovation ManagementMaster of Social WorkBachelor of Arts in Legal StudiesBachelor of Arts in PsychologyBachelor of Business AdministrationParalegal Studies CertificateBusiness - Post-Baccalaureate CertificateEducation - Post-Baccalaureate CertificatePsychology - Post-Baccalaureate CertificateMarriage and Family Sciences - Post-Baccalaureate CertificateBusiness - Post-Master's CertificateEducation - Post-Master's CertificatePsychology - Post-Master's CertificateMarriage and Family Sciences - Post-Master's CertificateNot Sure
Specialization *
Select a Specialization
About Me
First Name *
Last Name *
Email *
Phone *
Numbers only. e.g. 8885551212
Zip Code *
As an affiliate of the National University system, by submitting your information to Northcentral University, you agree to NCU’s Privacy Policy and acknowledge that Northcentral University has your authorization to provide your information to its affiliates in the National University System, and that such affiliates are authorized to contact you regarding their educational programs via automated means, including emails, calls, or text messages to your wireless phone if provided.
As a regionally accredited online university, Northcentral University has the privilege of serving students worldwide. Just as we are interested in learning more about you and your educational and career aspirations, we hope you’ll take the time to get to know us, discover how our programs and services work to reflect our Mission, Vision and Values, and our commitment to excellence in everything we do.
About
Mission
History
Diversity
Accreditations
Graduation Rates
Strategic Partnerships
Admissions
